Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/avisha-jaiswal-65b4b7148 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Deep Learning
Machine Learning
Business Analysis

Avisha Jaiswal

Former Research Intern at IIIT Hyderabad || Deep Learning || Machine Learning || NLP

Raipur

Summary

As an undergraduate of an institution of National importance, I have a decent academic background. I served as a Summer Research Intern at Language Technologies & Research Center(LTRC), IIIT Hyderabad, the largest of its kind in entire South Asia, where I worked on Natural Language Processing and various Machine Learning Algorithms to build a system for Named Entity Recogniser for Indian Judiciary and a Question Answering System to answer the day to day queries of Indian farmers regarding crops diseases. I also served as a Web Development and Business Requirements Intern at Aditya Birla Capital for a period of one month. I also worked on a project to develop a website for a FoodTech startup, Garden Of Taste, that delivers subscription-based customised meals, and also served as Digital Marketing and Content Writing Intern for the same. I have built an automated vehicle detection model to detect vehicles in no parking zone which involved working closely with machine learning techniques. I have a little experience in marketing as well as I served as the Marketing Manager of the Marketing team of the pilot edition of TEDxNITRAIPUR. Apart from working on my technical skills, I've also written and presented a research paper on the topic "Language and Gender- Stereotyping a Woman's Portrayal", at National Conference on Humanities and Social Sciences Held at NIT Raipur.

Experience

TEDxNITRaipur
Head Coordinator
January 2017 - Present (3 years 8 months)
Raipur, Chattisgarh, India

IIIT Hyderabad Summer Research Intern May 2018 - July 2018 (3 months) Hyderabad, Telangana, India

Aditya Birla Health Insurance Company Limited 2 months

Software and Web Development Intern December 2017 - January 2018 (2 months)

Mumbai, Maharashtra, India

Business Requirements Intern December 2017 - January 2018 (2 months)

Mumbai, Maharashtra, India

HAPPY-LAB

Web Development and Digital Marketing Intern June 2017 - July 2017 (2 months)

Coimbatore

Education

National Institute of Technology Raipur
Bachelor of Technology, Information Technology · (2015 - 2019)